Guide to the R. B. Jones papers.
Jones, R. B. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
R. B. Jones papers.
4901
R. B., Jones 1920-
3.6 cubic ft.
Files, papers, audiodiscs, audiotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files and working papers pertaining to the study of southeast Asian languages; also, audiodiscs and audiotapes.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor, Cornell University.
R. B. Jones was a peer of John Echols and developed the mainland Southeast Asia Program at Cornell. He was a major contributor to the nation's teaching capacity in Burmese, Thai, and Vietnamese languages. His original field is in Karen languages.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files and working papers pertaining to the study of southeast Asian languages; also, audiodiscs and audiotapes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Jones, R. B., 1920-; Echols, John M. (John Minor), 1912-1982; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Southeast Asia Program.
Subjects:
Burmese language.; Vietnamese language.; Karen language.; Japanese language.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Papers
  - Karen Papers (Keyes) [Karen History in Thai and Ethic Relations] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Karen Pronunciation Charts (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Karen Tones (Problems with) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Karen Working Notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Karen Panel (Letters regarding the place of the Karen in Asia) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Karen Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Intro. to Karen and Info. of Syo Dialect (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - R. Burling on Karen (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mason's Grammar (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Phonetic Chart and Tone Info. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Phonetic Charts (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Luce Word List (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Luce-Karen-Chin-Burma (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Karen (Shaler: Sino-Tibetan, 1974) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Karen Drum (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Karen Drum 2 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sgaw Writing System (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Key to Karen Writing and Kinship System (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Sketches of Pa-O Grammar (Hacket 1954) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Tibeto-Burmese (Lepcha Relationships) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Palaychi (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Yao-Miao (Purnell) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Proto-Vietnamoung (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cambodian Writing System (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Burmese Grammar (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Vietnamese-Muong (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Hari-Mid. Vietnamese -de Rates (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Seminar Papers of Tran Trong Hai (on Vietnam) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cambodian Notes (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Comabodian Notes 2 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Mon-Khmer Articles (Sre and Palauna) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Burma Inscriptions (Payan, Dhammayan, Gyi Pilar, and Pyu) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Burmese (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Burmese Kinship (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Burmese Semester 1976 - Karen/Valley Forge (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Karen Linguistic Affiliation (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Burmese (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Prolegomena to a Homology of Old Burmese (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Two Methods of Interpreting Panini (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Types of Lingusitic Structure - Hass (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lang Structure (Finnish, Hungarian) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sea Languages (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sea Languages (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Phunoi (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lahu (Verb Concatenation) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - GMC (Etomology, Pie Phonology, Morphology) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nasu (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hani (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Sani (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Generative Sketch on Burmese (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Proto Chinese (History) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Lahu and Proto-Lio-Burmese (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Akha (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Akha (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Transformal Analysis of tone in verb system of Zahao (Laizo) Chin - Thesis (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Thai Discourse - Diller (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Thai Discourse Analysis - Final Report (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Thai Discourse - Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Parataxis Diagrams (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Final Report Notes (Discourse, Principal of Chaloem at School) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Discourse Analysis of Japanese and Thai (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Sino-Tibetan Conference - Contents Lists (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Fifth Conference of Sino-Tibetan Lang (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sixth Conference of Sino-Tibetan Lang (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Eighth Conference of Sino-Tibetan Lang (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Eleventh Conference of Sino-Tibetan Lang (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Thirteenth Conference of Sino-Tibetan Lang (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Working Papers in Linguistics (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - James Matisoff (Lahu and Lolo) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - William Gedney (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Historical Place of Jinghpaw (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lolo (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Tibetan Tones (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Tonal System (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Proto-Yiang (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miao-Yao (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Archaic Chinese (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chinese (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Chinese Dialects (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cantonese (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Maru Fonal Stops (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Arkanese Vowels (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Performativity and Conjoining (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Burmese Reading Course (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Austro-Thai (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Dental Suffixes (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Syntactic Reconstruction (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Burmese (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Misc. Burmese (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence regarding Karen Thesaurus/Dictionary (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Phonetic Charts (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Outline of Burmese Grammar (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sino Tibetan (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Burmese Translation (Possible Temple Inscriptions) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Fiend Notes (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Fiend Notes (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Fiend Notes (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Burmese Dialects (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Misc. Information (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Information (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Misc. Information (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Misc. Information (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Phonetic Charts (Box 4)
  - Phonodiscs, Japanese and Karen (Box 5)
  - Regional Science Correspondence; 1983, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Etude sur la phonetique historique de la langue annamite, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Study in Po-Ai dialects, notes and paper, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Tai alphabet prepared by Coedes and word lists (Lefevre-Pontalis), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Elemental Burmese (U Khin), Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minzu Yuwen Vol. 1-5, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Minzu Yuwen Vol. 3 (1983), Vol 2-6 (1984), Vol. 1 (1986), 1983-1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Derung language treatise, 1982-02 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Robert A. Hall's publications, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Old Mon (Burmese) glossary, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Working papers in phonetics and phonology vol.1 no.1, 1976-04 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Indic scripts (Sgaw and Shan) photocopy, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Proto-Burmese material, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - A comparative word-list of old Burmese, Chinese, and Tibetan, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Journal of the Burma research society, 1959-06 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Sino-Tibetan and Burmese vocabulary and paper, Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Consonant mergers Anthony V. N. Diller, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Burmese-Mon alphabet, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - A handbook of Asian scripts, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Indic alphabets, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The center for Burma studies, newsletter and bulletin, 1987-08-1987-10 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Thai word list Brian Hartnell, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Urom Warofamasikkhadit Papers, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Ethnic adaptation and identity, the Karen on the Thai frontier with Burma, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Army intensive Japanese school day, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Tai Mao, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - La langue et la culture Lao, 1957-11-18 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Black Tai, Tho (Black, White), Riviere Claire, 1907-1910 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Siam dialects, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Lung-Chow (Li), Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Thai comparative work, Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Thai dialects comparative workand articles, 1967-1973 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Tho Syntax (Day), (Lagua, Lao Blanc), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Daic, Introduction to Sino-Tibetan, Robert Shafer, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tai Tones Diagrams, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Kam, Mu Lam, Minzu Yuwen Vol. 2 (1980), Vol. 4 (1982), Vol. 1,2,5,6 (1983), Vol. 1 (1984), 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hainan Li (Shibel, Meriggi), 1982-08 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hainan Be, Minzu Yuwen Vol. 4 (1983), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Li, White Thai, Nung (F), 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Tai Nua, Harris, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Lu, Saek, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Li, T'en, Fang-Kuei Li, 1967-1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Red, Black, White Tai, Gedney, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - White Tai, Donaldson, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Nung, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Nung Synthax, Freiberger, 1981-05-23 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Tho (Lang Son), Dictionary (Day), Comparative Papers, 1959-03-17 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Anthropological Linguistics Vol. 1 No. 2, 1959-02 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Languages and dialects of China, Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Ning, Ming, Gedney, 1973-10 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Wu-Ming, Li, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Laotian (Luang Prabang), Kieley, 1955-05 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Thai comparative studies, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - The question of Karen linguistic affiliation, Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Karen lessons Sgaw, Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - The Karens of Burma, Marshall, 1945-05 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - The golden book, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Sgaw Karen letters, elementary children, new readers, 1979-01 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Sonagrams, Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Worksheets for a first course in transformational synthax, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Grammaticalization and syntactic change, Diller, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - In search of a Tai syntactic change, 1993-09-23 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Bulletin of Burma studies group No. 51, 1994-01 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - The underground transformer, Noss, 1972-12 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - An outline for metalinguistic analysis, Henry L. Smith Jr., 1952-06-20 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Pre-standard old Burmese 1 of 2, 1973-05 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    Stone inscriptions, ink glosses, and votive tablets
  - Pre-standard old Burmese 2 of 2, 1973-05 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Photos and slides from Lokatheikpan Temple, Burma, Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Loan words, paper by R.B. Jones Jr., Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Asian language journals, 1970, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Uncommonly taught languages, 1960-1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Language conferences, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Survey for an appropriate program of research (southeast asian languages), Fall 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Conference on a survey of personnel, materials, and programs for the teaching of Southeast Asian languages, determination of needs and recommendations for an appropriate program of research, 1959-12-17-1959-12-18 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Karen, descriptive and comparative studies with texts, R.B. Jones Jr., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Final report, discourse analysis of Japanese and Thai, 1976-06 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Japanese, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Thai cultural reader reviews, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Language learning and interpreting (Dept. of State), 1942-1979 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Analysis of culture, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Karen linguistic studies, R.B. Jones Jr., 1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Comparative method L. 502, Tai, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Chuang, Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Sui, Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Kam dictionary, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Japanese discourse, 1976-06 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Various notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Relations of Cambodia, 1958-1973 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Poetry notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Thai writing system, Undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Pa-Po, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Tone, 1940-1970 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Proto-Burmese, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Vocabulary charts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Linguistic Articles, 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Bisu articles, 1976-1987 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Megyaw Hpun, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Bisu, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Proto-Burmese, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Dialects of Burma tables, Taylor, 1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Reviews, 1968-1970, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Laryngeals and the development of tones in Karen, R.B. Jones Jr., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1958, 1966, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Note Thai dialect maps, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Roogrian Chaleemsaat, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Conversation with Khanchoy Bunpan, Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Thai tone maps and tables, Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - On the reality of reconstructed languages, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Assorted articles, 1965-1978 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lolo-Burmese, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - A grammar of the Burmese language, Judson, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Library, romanization, Burmese, 1971, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Haurgood, Creaky tone, Burmese, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Papers and reviews sent for publishing, 1969-1975 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Pitch register, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Proto-Burmese test of reconstruction, 1978-1989 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence ACLS, 1953-1960 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Articles and notes, 1972-1977, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Pu-Yi (Kwei-chow) dialect atlas 1 of 2, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Pu-Yi (Kwei-chow) dialect atlas 2 of 2, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Ling. notes, 1949-1952, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Outline of Thai grammar, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Four articles on metalinguistics, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bibliographies, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Ling. 271-(2) Sea, 1962-01 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Conversations for foreign students of English, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Studies on Dempwolff, Lopez, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Vietnamese and Thai articles, 1955, 1959, 1962-1964 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Classics 196: Indo-European grammar, Undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Special papers, voice production, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Tone, 1977-1978, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Tone Course, 1974-1981 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Bibliography, comparativge method, 1957-1969 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Comparative method articles, 1946-1981 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Studies in Thai dialectology, Egerod, Undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Workbook in comparative reconstruction, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Ling. 404 course problem Keresan, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Introductory workbook in historical phonology, Columbus, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Misc. notes and exercises, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Lu, Tai, Li, Undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Future directions in comparative Tai linguistics, Gedney, Undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Laryngeal features and tone development, Li, Fall 1985 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - A new look at the history and classification of the Tai languages, Chamberlain, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Chinese and Thai: morpheme correspondences, draft 5, 1966-02 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Karen Language Card Files (Box 11)
  - Karen Language Card Files (Box 12)
  - Sonagrams, Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sgaw Karen Lessons 2, Ballard, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Sgaw Karen Lessons 1, Ballard, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Pwo Karen lessons, Morris, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Pwo Karen dictionary J-Y, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Pwo Karen dictionary A-I, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Vocabulary charts, Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Linguistic notes, Undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Reprints, 1958-1975 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Portfolio of language exercises and notes, Undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Notes, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Thai dialects, papers and correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Myang dialect (Mundhenk), Undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Burmese literature draft for submission to Litterature d'Oriente, Undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Essays offered to G.H. Luce Vol. 1, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Vocabulaire francais, Thay blanc et elements de grammaire Vol. 1 & 2, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Po-Ai, Pu-Yi, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Kam, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Chuang (Kwansi), Serdychenko (Diller), 1961-1963, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Ge Lao, Minzu Yuwen Vol. 4, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Vocabulary charts, Undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Vocabulary charts, Undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, Undated (Box 14)
  - College notebooks and fieldnotes, 1957-1958 (Box 15)
  - The ancient Khmer Empire, 1951 (Box 15)
    Issued as volume 41, part 1, of the transactions of the American Philosophical Society
- Audio material
  - Examples from Jane Kielgs MA Thesis, tr-6996
  - Laotian (BASSAC Dialect), tr-7997
  - Lautian (BASIC Dialects), tr-6998
  - Burmese Broadcast, tr-6999
  - Karen Bassein Phu Dialect, tr-7000
  - Northern Thai, tr-7001
  - Thai Stress, tr-7002
  - Thai Poetry, tr-7003
  - Thai Poetry 2, tr-7004
  - Thai Poetry 3, tr-7005
  - Dunn Tape, tr-7006
  - Karen, tr-7007
  - Examples from Jane Kielgs MA Thesis (Bk), tr-7008
  - Converstaion: Mailmein Phokaren, tr-7009
  - Stories, tr-7010
  - Laos I, tr-7011
  - Laos II, tr-7012
  - Japanese and Karen Record, tr-7013
  - Mopwa, Undated; tr-16735 (Box 13)
    Audiocassette
  - BWE light/heavy, Undated; tr-16736 (Box 13)
  - Jean Donaldson's tape, Undated; tr-16737 (Box 13)
  - RBJ - English resonants, Undated; tr-16738 (Box 13)
  - Unlabeled tape, Undated; tr-16739 (Box 13)
  - Unlabeled tape, Undated; tr-16740 (Box 13)
  - Candid tape recordings of casual conversations and events, Undated; tr-16741-16744 (Box 13)
    Manora, Thai, Pali
  - British English, Undated; tr-16745 (Box 13)
  - Thai dialects, Undated; tr-16746 (Box 13)
    Audiotape reel
  - Unlabeled tape, Undated; tr-16747 (Box 13)
  - BWE Karen - Naw Tha Saw, Undated; tr-16748 (Box 13)
    Light/heavy consonant contrasts (using English monosyllables)
  - Mopwa Karen (Palaychi), Undated; tr-16749 (Box 13)